Alessio Santoru | Curriculum Vitae

♠ +39 3774399335

■ alessiosantoru@gmail.com ↑ https://github.com/santoru • https://insecurity.blog

Profile

A Senior Product Security Engineer with a strong focus in offensive security and vulnerability research, most recently in the financial industry. A passionate security blog writer and part time bug hunter, equipped with a strong intercultural and interdisciplinary mindset.

About me

Date of birth: 01/01/1994

Citizenship: Italian

Based in: Berlin, Germany

Certifications

OSCP: Offensive Security Certified Professional

Languages

Italian: First language

English: Intermediate - B2

German: Basic - A1

Skills and passions

Security:

- Web application
- Mobile application
- Logic vulnerabilities

Programming languages:

Python, Java, PHP, C, Go,

Shell scripting

Technologies: Docker, AWS

Softwares: BurpSuite, Nessus, sqlmap, nmap, netcat, Hopper disassembler, git

Other:

- Bug bounty hunter on multiple platforms with several vulnerabilities reported to vendors
- Several open source tools developed or contributed
- Security blog writer

Work experience

Senior Product Security Engineer

Trade Republic, Berlin

October, 2021 - Present

- Strengthen the security resilience postures of internal and external facing services based on an in-depth understanding of the engineering team's needs
- Define and discover threats, risks and vulnerabilities by leveraging threat modelling, code review, penetration testing skills and an attacker mindset
- o Build internal software to automate processes, support SSDLC and other security initiatives.
- Perform proactive research to detect new attack vectors and vulnerabilities present in third parties

Product Security Engineer

N26, Berlin

November, 2019 - September 2021

- Ensured security of mobile, web and API by performing threat modelling and penetration
- Developed internal tools to automate the security test processes
- Safeguarded the systems through vulnerability research and penetration test activities of third party softwares
- Implemented the Security Champions training to cover Security 101, Threat Modelling and OWASP Top 10

Security Consultant

Horizon Security, Milan

April, 2017 - October, 2019

- Executed penetration test and vulnerability assessment Web and Mobile Applications / Hardware and IoT devices
- Conducted reverse engineering activities of mobile applications iOS / Android
- Performed vulnerability research and responsible disclosure to vendors

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science

Italy

Università degli Studi di Perugia

2017

Final mark: 110/110

Erasmus+ Student (Computer Science)

Poland

Politechnika Krakowska im. Tadeusza Kościuszki

2016

Achievements

CVE-2018-20122: Remote code execution in Fastweb FASTgate router

CVE-2018-17172: Command injection in Xerox Altalink's web application

CVE-2018-7064: Cross-site scripting (XSS) Reflected in Aruba Instant web interface

CVE-2017-17663: Buffer overflow in mini httpd/thttpd

Public speaking

2017: Real-time Auditing on macOS with OpenBSM

University of Utah, MacAdmins Meeting